Authkit just added permissions,
which means that you
can now implement RBAC
for all of your million
free monthly active users.
This video is everything you need to know
to get started with
role-based authorization
in your applications.
Let's get into it.
For this tutorial, we're using the next-
authkit-example app.
Here you'll find instructions for cloning
and setting up the application.
And once set up, it looks
like this running locally.
The first thing you need to know
is that permissions are now
available on user sessions.
We can see this in the src/
/app/account/ page source file.
Using authkit-next to
get the user session,
we now have user role and permissions,
which we can hover to see its type,
undefined or an array of strings.
After signing into our application,
we can visit the account page
where we see our user data,
our role, but no permissions.
So let's go into our WorkOS
dashboard under roles
to create new permissions.
Now, when I see new forms like this,
I'm always a little bit worried
that I'm gonna screw something up.
So I'll give you a little guidance
on how to use these fields,
but we have a wonderful article
that goes into much more detail.
Let's say that we wanna
add a post viewer role.
The name field is required,
but can be changed later on
if you come up with a better name.
Slug on the other hand
is the technical string
that we're going to use
inside of our application
to permit or restrict
different behaviors.
So I use database and crud style language
saying that for posts, we
want to permit read access.
Finally, the description is optional,
but helpful for
providing additional information.
I'm gonna leave it blank for now though.
So we have our viewer permission.
Let's add a full access permission.
For now, I'll call this a post admin.
And for the resource type of
posts, they have full access.
Great, now I have two permissions.
Now, one thing to note is that these
slugs are immutable.
So even though we can
change the name and description,
the slug can be edited after creation.
Now that we have our permissions set up,
let's go about adding them to roles.
In role-based access control,
the best practice is to run your
authorization checks
against permissions, not roles.
However, you can't apply
permissions directly to users.
You apply them through roles.
By default, every user in
Authkit has a member role.
So to apply permissions to that role,
we navigate to the role we want to edit
and add permissions.
Here, I'll select posts read.
Now, every user with that
role has that new permission.
Back in our application,
we can validate that by
signing out and signing back in.
Visit the account page, and here we go.
We have both our role, member, and
permission, posts read.
Okay, but why did I log
out to log back in again?
I did this to force refresh the session.
By default, Authkit sessions
refresh every five minutes,
but that value can be
configured based on your needs.
For the sake of this tutorial,
it's just easier to log
out and log back in again.
While we're in the WorkOS dashboard,
let's jump back to roles
and create a new admin role.
Using lowercase admin as a slug
and the description full system access,
we'll add the permission, posts all,
create our new role,
find a user to assign it to,
under organizations, edit role,
change from member to admin.
Now this user has an admin role,
which changes the
permissions that they have in the app.
Jump back over to the
app, sign out, sign in again,
and see that our
account now has an admin role
with the updated permissions.
And that's all there is to it.
Now that you have permissions,
you can do permissions
checks against those string slugs
and restrict or enable
features based on those permissions.
Of course, there are two things
that I wanna call out before leaving you.
First and foremost,
you'll wanna use the
latest version of our SDKs,
whichever framework you are using.
Second, you wanna
check out the documentation
for roles and permissions.
Here you'll find great suggestions
on how to model your application,
what to name the slugs,
depending on your application needs,
and even suggestions on
which delimiters to use.
This is an extremely well considered doc
and you should give it a look.
Okay, so we talked about roles,
we talked about permissions.
I think that's pretty much it for today,
but we're currently in
the middle of a series
where we're integrating AuthKit into any
JavaScript framework.
That sounds like your jam.
Check out one of these videos over here.
I'm chantastic, I'll see
you in the next one, bye.