Preview deploys from
companies like Vercel, Netlify,
CloudFlare, and more
make it easy for you to see
every commit in your Git tree
as a live production deploy.
But this can make things difficult
when integrating with other services
that require a redirect URI.
We have a lot of questions about this
from developers looking
to connect hosted AuthKit
in their preview deploys.
So today I'll show you a
quick and foolproof way
to connect with two.
Let's get into it.
On the screen I'm
running the local version
of my personal site.
And if I attempt to visit the dashboard,
I'll be redirected to my
hosted AuthKit login page.
If we investigate this URL,
we see a handful of query parameters,
including my client ID
as well as a redirect URI.
This URI is obviously encoded,
but if you look at it,
you can see that we're
sending users back to local host,
port 2426 slash auth slash callback
once they've been authenticated.
Of course, this is a known
value in my local environment,
but it's dynamic in a
preview deploy setting.
So let's go to Cloudflare
where this site is hosted,
find a preview URL and open it up.
Now, when I attempt to
visit the dashboard page
in this preview deploy, we get an error.
Now, what we need is a
way to get this dynamic URL
for this specific build into two places,
our sign in URL and
our WorkOS dashboard.
So let's copy it and
navigate to our work OS dashboard
where we will visit the redirects page.
Here we see our local
URL in our allow list.
So let's add our preview deploy.
Now, preview deploys
follow some type of pattern.
This is the site and the domain.
And before that is the ID of the build.
This is the part that's
going to change most frequently.
So it will represent the
dynamic part with an asterisk,
which we can see is
used as a wildcard value.
Add that and we should be
good on the work OS side.
Now let's take a look at the code.
On our sign in page,
we are redirecting to an
authkit authorization URL,
which we get through our
authkit local library package.
So let's inspect that function.
The get authorization URL
requires three pieces of data,
the provider authkit, the
redirect URI and the client ID.
Now, because we want a
dynamic redirect URI,
I'm gonna cut this and
call an accessor function.
We'll then write a function that checks
if we even have a WorkOS
redirect URI in our environment,
return it if we do and
throw an error if we don't.
Now this is where it gets interesting.
In CloudFlare, we can
add a second condition
that will check for the
preview deployment URL.
In CloudFlare, that's cf_pages_url.
And in this case, render the preview URL
with our URI segments
attached to the end of it.
With this function in place,
we can now leave our work
OS redirect URI environment
variable undefined only in
our preview deploy environment
and depend on this cf_pages_url instead.
Let's say this commit and push.
Now back on our hosting platform,
we'll see this new build.
And once it's deployed,
we'll see a unique build URL.
This time when we try
to visit our dashboard
and get redirected to
authkit, we find success.
And finding our redirect URI parameter,
the proper dynamic preview deploy URL.
This means that we can
log in and be directed back
to this specific preview deploy.
So that's all you need to do to make sure
that hosted authkit is available
for all of your preview deploys.
If you found a particularly good article
on how to do this for
your specific platform,
please put them in the comments below.
I'm sure others would love to see them.
And if you have other
questions, we'd love to hear them
and help you get started with AuthKit.
I'm chantastic, I'll see
you in the next one, bye.